<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[English-Notes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>English-Notes</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 06:08:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 06:08:55 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Quote Table]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Reputation (n.): The beliefs or opinions that are generally held about someone or something<br>In Salem, reputation held no bargaining value once a person was placed on trial. Yet still, we see characters fight to save their reputation with their life AND integrity on the line. It can be said that characters "think through reputation".<br><br><br>Fear (n.): An unpleasant emotion caused by the threat of danger, pain, or harm.<br>
Hysteria (n.): Exaggerated or uncontrollable emotion or excitement.<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\quote-table.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Quote Table.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 05:43:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Context]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><a data-href="Arthur Miller" href="\common-module-the-crucible\arthur-miller.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Arthur Miller</a> wrote The Crucible as a reaction to the House Un-American Activities Committee's (HUAC) actions, and the dangers of McCarthyism that was consuming America in the 1950s.<br><br><br>Salem Witch Trials<br><br>
<br>Miller's Interest in the Salem witch trials was prompted after reading Marion Starkey's The Devil In Massachusetts (1949), which suggested that attitudes towards race and nationality during the Second World War which made the Salem Witch Trials an allegory for that period
<br>Miller found the core of his plot in Charles W. Upham's 1867 Salem Witchcraft, in which all the play's characters referred to and many of its events related. He also read the original court transcripts
<br>Salem was settled in 1629. In January 1692, the Reverend Parris's daughter, Betty, aged nine, and her cousin, Abigail, aged eleven, apparently be came afflicted with contortions and fits, making complaints about being pinched and pricked with pins
<br>Miller condensed and altered some of the characters to better fit the play and his message
<br><br><br>HUAC<br><br>The House Un-America Activities Committee (HUAC)<br>
<br>Miller wrote The Crucible 3 years before his hearing in front of the HUAC
<br>
]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\context\context.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Context/Context.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HUAC]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The House Un-America Activities Committee (HUAC)<br>
<br>Miller wrote The Crucible 3 years before his hearing in front of the HUAC
<br>
]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\context\huac.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Context/HUAC.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Salem Witch Trials]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Miller's Interest in the Salem witch trials was prompted after reading Marion Starkey's The Devil In Massachusetts (1949), which suggested that attitudes towards race and nationality during the Second World War which made the Salem Witch Trials an allegory for that period
<br>Miller found the core of his plot in Charles W. Upham's 1867 Salem Witchcraft, in which all the play's characters referred to and many of its events related. He also read the original court transcripts
<br>Salem was settled in 1629. In January 1692, the Reverend Parris's daughter, Betty, aged nine, and her cousin, Abigail, aged eleven, apparently be came afflicted with contortions and fits, making complaints about being pinched and pricked with pins
<br>Miller condensed and altered some of the characters to better fit the play and his message
]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\context\salem-witch-trials.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Context/Salem Witch Trials.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fear and Hysteria]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>noun: an&nbsp;unpleasant&nbsp;emotion caused by the threat of danger, pain, or harm.<br>
verb: be afraid of (someone or something) as likely to be dangerous, painful, or harmful.<br><br>noun: exaggerated or uncontrollable emotion or excitement.<br><br>Hysteria is the reaction and culmination of fear reaching a heightened or uncontrollable state.<br><br>Fear feeds into the hysterical state while heightened hysteria produces additional fear. This creates an intense cycle that spirals out of control.<br><br>People in The Crucible act paradoxically and inconsistently leading to and due to fear and hysteria.]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\themes\fear-and-hysteria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Themes/Fear and Hysteria.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reputation]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>In Parris, we see consequences when reputation is chosen over integrity:<br>
<br>Hathorne: "(Parris) has a mad look these days... I think it is not well the village see him so unsteady."
<br>Parris: "Judge Hathorne - It were another sort that hanged till now."
<br><br>
<br>Parris : "(Elizabeth) comes so rarely to the church this year for she will not sit so close to something soiled."
<br><br>
<br>Proctor: "Tell them I confessed myself say Proctor boke his knees and wept like a woman; say what you will but my name cannot-"
<br>Proctor: "A man will not cast away his good name."
<br>Proctor: with a cry of his whole soul: "Because it is my name! Because I cannot have another in my life! Because I lie and sign myself to lies! Because I am not worth the dust on the feet of them that hang! How may I live without my name? I have given you my soul; leave me my name!"
<br>Parris: "It is a weighty name; it will strike the village that Proctor confess."
<br>Proctor: "I have made a bell of my honour! I have rung the doom of my good name."
<br>Proctor: "God in Heaven, what is John Proctor, what is John Proctor? (He moves as an animal) ..."
]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\themes\reputation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Themes/Reputation.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Themes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Reputation *is more valuable than integrity
<br>Power &amp; Authority *should never rule
<br>Fear &amp; Hysteria *easily corrupt
<br>Manipulation *effectively positions self and others
<br><br>
<br>Themes help guide our thinking to what the purpose of the text is. 

<br>What is the composer attempting to convey? 


<br>Themes provide insight into what cultures value (original and contemporary). 

<br>What is being valued in the text, and how does this resonate with an audience


<br>Themes are dynamic. They emerge from an intimate relationship between composer and responder and text and culture. 
<br>Mastering themes on a deeper, conceptual level will enrich your analysis

<br>Basic: Top-level idea, what's in front of you
<br>Extended: Significance, implied meaning

<br>What is being said about this idea?




]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\themes\themes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Themes/Themes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Arthur Miller]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Arthur Miller (1915-2005) was born in Harlem, New York into a Jewish family. <br>Known for:<br>
<br>All my sons
<br>The Crucible
<br>The death of a salesman
<br><br>During the tense era of McCarthyism, celebrated playwright Arthur Miller was inspired to write a drama reflecting the mass cultural and political hysteria when the U.S. government sought to suppress Communism and radical leftist activity in America.<br>Arthur Miller wrote a play called "The Crucible" as an allegory of McCarthyism, inspired by the U.S. government's efforts to suppress Communism in America and how its affects on society.]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\arthur-miller.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Arthur Miller.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Character List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A farmer in Salem, Proctor serves as the voice of reason and justice in The Crucible. It is he who exposes the girls as frauds who are only pretending that there is witchcraft, and thus becomes the tragic hero of the tale. Proctor is a sharply intelligent man who can easily detect foolishness in others and expose it, but he questions his own moral sense. Because of his affair with Abigail Williams, Proctor questions whether or not he is a moral man, yet this past event is the only major flaw attributed to Proctor, who is in all other respects honourable and ethical. It is a sign of his morality that he does not feel himself adequate to place himself as a martyr for the cause of justice when he is given the choice to save himself at the end of the play.<br><br>The wife of John Proctor, Elizabeth shares with John a similarly strict adherence to justice and moral principles She is a woman who has great confidence in her own morality and in the ability of a person to maintain a sense of righteousness, both internal and external, even when this principle conflicts with strict Christian doctrine. Although she is regarded as a woman of unimpeachable honesty, it is this reputation that causes her husband to be condemned when she lies about his affair with Abigail, thinking it will save him. However, Elizabeth can be a cold and demanding woman, whose chilly demeanour may have driven her husband to adultery and whose continual suspicions of her husband render their marriage tense.<br><br>A seventeen year-old girl who is the niece of Reverend Parris, Abigail was the Proctors' servant before Elizabeth fired her for having an affair with John. She is a malicious, vengeful girl who, in an attempt to protect herself from punishment after Reverend Parris finds them dancing, instigates the Salem witch trials and leads the charge of accusations. Despite her accusations, Abigail is an unabashed liar who charges witchcraft against those who oppose her, even Elizabeth Proctor in an attempt to take her place as Proctor's wife. Abigail's callous nature stems partially from past trauma; she is an orphan who watched as her parents were murdered by Indians.<br><br>The deputy governor of  Massachusetts presides over the Salem witch trials. He is a stern yet practical man more interested in preserving the dignity and stature of the court than in executing justice or behaving with any sense of fairness. He approaches the witchcraft trials with a strict adherence to rules and law that obscure any sense of rationality, for under his legal dictates an accusation of witchery automatically entails a conviction. Danforth shows that his greatest interest is preserving the reputation of the court when he prompts Proctor to sign a confession, thus precluding the backlash of his execution.<br><br>A weak, paranoid and suspicious demagogue, Parris instigates the witchcraft panic when he finds his daughter and niece dancing in the woods with several other girls. Parris is continually beset with fears that others conspire against him. Parris knows the truth that Abigail is lying about the dancing and the witchcraft, but perpetuates the deception because it is in his own self interest. Parris fears any defence against the charges of witchcraft as an attack upon the court and a personal attack on him. As a pastor, his primary concern is personal aggrandizement - he strives for monetary compensation, including the deed to the preacher's house and expensive candlesticks. <br><br>A scholar from Beverly, Reverend Hale comes to Salem on Reverend Parris' request to investigate supernatural causes for Betty Parris' suspicious illness and thus instigates the rumours of witchcraft. Hale approaches the situation precisely and intellectually, believing that he can define the supernatural in definitive terms. Despite his early enthusiasm for discerning the presence of witchcraft in Salem, Hale soon grows disillusioned with the witchcraft accusations that abound and defends Proctor when he challenges Abigail. Hale does this out of guilt, for he fears that he may have caused the execution of innocent persons. <br><br>An irascible and combative old resident of Salem, Giles Corey is a comic figure in The Crucible whose fate turns tragic when he unwittingly effects his wife's charge for witchcraft when he wonders aloud about the strange books she reads at night. Corey is a frequent plaintiff in court, having brought dozens of lawsuits, and he stands with Proctor in challenging the girls' accusations, believing that Thomas Putnam is using charges of witchcraft to secure land. When Corey refuses to name the person who heard Putnam declare these intentions, Corey is charged with contempt of court and dies when the court orders him to be weighted with stones to coerce him to admit the name. <br><br>The eighteen year-old servant in the Proctor household, Mary is one of the girls found dancing in the woods and is complicit in Abigail Williams' schemes. Although weak and tentative, she challenges the Proctors when they forbid her to go to court. However, Mary eventually breaks down and testifies against Abigail until Abigail charges her with witchery. She is a pliable girl whose actions are easily determined by others. <br><br>Parris' slave from Barbados, Tituba was with the girls when they danced and attempted to conjure the spirits of Ann Putnam's dead children. She is the first person accused of witchcraft and likewise the first person to accuse others of witchery - particularly when she discovers that the easiest way to spare herself is to admit to the charges no matter their truth.<br><br>One of the wealthiest landowners in Salem, Thomas Putnam is a vindictive, bitter man who holds longstanding grudges against many of the citizens of Salem, including the Nurse family for blocking the appointment of his brother-in-law to the position of minister. Putnam pushes his daughter to charge witchcraft against George Jacobs, for if he is executed, his land will be open for Putnam to purchase. <br><br>One of the most noble and well-respected citizens of Salem, this elderly woman is kindly and sane, suggesting that Betty's illness is simply a product of being out too late in the cold. However, because she served as midwife to Mrs. Putnam, Rebecca Nurse is charged with the supernatural murder of Putnam's children, who were each stillborn. Rebecca Nurse is the clear martyr in the play, the most pure and saintly character hanged for witchery. <br><br>Hathorne is the judge who presides over the Salem witch trials. He remains largely subservient to Deputy Governor Danforth, but applies the same tortured reasoning to charges of witchcraft. <br><br>Francis is the husband of Rebecca Nurse, and a well-respected wealthy landowner in Salem. Francis Nurse joins Giles Corey and John Proctor in their challenge against the court when their respective wives are charged with witchcraft. <br><br>The young teenager daughter of Reverend Parris, Betty falls mysteriously ill after Reverend Parris finds her dancing in the woods with Abigail and the other young women of Salem. She goes into hysterics when the charges of witchcraft first form, holding delusions that she can fly and exclaiming with horror when she hears the name of Jesus. <br><br>One of the first women charged with witchery by the girls, she is a homeless woman who confesses to witchcraft to save herself and continues the charade with Tituba, comically claiming that Satan will take her and Tituba to Barbados. <br><br>Ezekiel is a clerk of the court who serves the arrest warrants to the persons charged with witchcraft. <br><br>The wife of Thomas Putnam, Ann suspects that there is some paranormal reason for the stillborn deaths of seven of her children and blames Rebecca Nurse. <br><br>Mercy Lewis is the Putnam's servant - a fat, sly merciless eighteen year-old girl whom Parris found naked when he spied the girls dancing in the woods. She runs away with Abigail at the end of the play. <br><br>Susanna is one of the girls whom Parris found dancing in the woods, and a confidant of Abigail. <br><br>Marshal is one of the local constables who guards the jail cells while nearly drunk.<br><br>Hopkins is one of the guards at the jail cell.]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\character-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Character List.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HSC Revision]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Reputation
<br>Power and Authority
<br>Fear and Hysteria
<br>Manipulation
<br><br>
<br>Evoking sensations of...
<br>Allowing responders to become enmeshed in the action/angst/drama...
<br>Clarifying the director's/composer's/author's position on...
]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\hsc-revision.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/HSC Revision.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Crucible Word List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Fervour: noun Intense and passionate feeling
<br>Ostracise: verb Exclude from a group or society
<br>McCarthyism: 

<br>verb The political practice of publicizing accusations of disloyalty or subversion with insufficient regard to evidence 
<br>noun The use of methods of investigation and accusation regarded as unfair, in order to suppress opposition


]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\the-crucible-word-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/The Crucible Word List.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Word List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Fervour: noun Intense and passionate feeling<br>
<br>Ostracise: verb Exclude from a group or society
<br>McCarthyism: 

<br>verb The political practice of publicizing accusations of disloyalty or subversion with insufficient regard to evidence 
<br>noun The use of methods of investigation and accusation regarded as unfair, in order to suppress opposition


]]></description><link>common-module-the-crucible\word-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Common Module - The Crucible/Word List.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Language, Identity, Culture]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Individual and collective identity is powerfully reflected and shaped in their language and word choice. This is clearly outlined when examining groups such as "car fans", music students and Australians. The language used by these groups form identities and stereotypes which attempt to connect these groups to their individuals.<br>One group, easily identifiable through their strong use of car-related jargon and dedication to their vehicles, pique a discussion in collective identity. Their constant discussion and mention of their car modification itinerary while simultaneously complaining about their lack of funds, explore a group comprised of mechanically devoted individuals identifiable through their on-topic language. This stereotype perfectly entertains the idea that individual and collective identity is heavily reflected in language.<br>Another substantial and interesting stereotype, music students, provide a window into the individuals and true identities that form the collective. Music students explore a split stereotype which can simultaneously define "muso's" as being heavily extroverted or heavily introverted individuals]]></description><link>module-a-henry-lawson\language,-identity,-culture.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module A - Henry Lawson/Language, Identity, Culture.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Christof]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Director of the Truman Show and manipulator of <a data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman Burbank</a>'s life
<br>Refers to himself as the "creator"
<br>His own name makes reference to his obvious God complex
<br>Thinks of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a> as his own son at times but at other times treats him as more of a commodity
<br>In a deeply nested piece of irony, he is an extremely private person, harshly contrasting his own show
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Characters/Christof.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marlon]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Played by the character Louis Coltrane
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> best friend since childhood
<br>Works as a vending machine filler/repairman
<br>Another one of [Christof]'s manipulative proxies to control Truman
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a> often confides in him. <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> will speak through Marlon to manipulate him
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\characters\marlon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Characters/Marlon.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Meryl Burbank]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Is a character in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> life played by Hannah Gill (actual character name)
<br>Married to <a data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman Burbank</a>
<br>Is offered a pay rise to have a child with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a> and is additionally paid $10,000 every time she sleeps with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a>
<br>Often blatantly weaves product placement into her conversations
<br>Works as an emergency room nurse
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\characters\meryl-burbank.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Characters/Meryl Burbank.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Truman Burbank]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Married to <a data-href="Meryl Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\meryl-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Meryl Burbank</a> with no children
<br>Fears water due to a traumatic experience with his fathers drowning
<br>Lives in <a data-href="Seahaven" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\seahaven.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Seahaven</a> with his wife and near his mother.
<br>Is the only genuine and real person in his hometown <a data-href="Seahaven" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\seahaven.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Seahaven</a>. All other townsfolk are actors
<br>Selected by Omnicom Corporation out of 6 unwanted newborns and became the first human legally adopted by a corporation.
<br>Best friends with <a data-href="Marlon" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\marlon.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Marlon</a> always turning to him for advice when issues arise
<br>Works as an insurance sales person
<br>His world his influenced, manipulated and watched by <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> the director of the Truman Show
<br>Truly in love with <a data-href="Sylvia" href="\Sylvia" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sylvia</a>, an actor-gone-rogue, who before she is removed from the set, tries to convince Truman that his world is fake and televised
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Characters/Truman Burbank.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[12-02-2024]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Limits of Artificially Constructed Reality
<br>Commercialism
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\12-02-2024.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/12-02-2024.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Character Profiles]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Truman Burbank<br><br>
<br>Married to <a data-href="Meryl Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\meryl-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Meryl Burbank</a> with no children
<br>Fears water due to a traumatic experience with his fathers drowning
<br>Lives in <a data-href="Seahaven" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\seahaven.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Seahaven</a> with his wife and near his mother.
<br>Is the only genuine and real person in his hometown <a data-href="Seahaven" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\seahaven.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Seahaven</a>. All other townsfolk are actors
<br>Selected by Omnicom Corporation out of 6 unwanted newborns and became the first human legally adopted by a corporation.
<br>Best friends with <a data-href="Marlon" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\marlon.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Marlon</a> always turning to him for advice when issues arise
<br>Works as an insurance sales person
<br>His world his influenced, manipulated and watched by <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> the director of the Truman Show
<br>Truly in love with <a data-href="Sylvia" href="\Sylvia" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sylvia</a>, an actor-gone-rogue, who before she is removed from the set, tries to convince Truman that his world is fake and televised
<br>
Christof<br><br>
<br>Director of the Truman Show and manipulator of <a data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman Burbank</a>'s life
<br>Refers to himself as the "creator"
<br>His own name makes reference to his obvious God complex
<br>Thinks of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a> as his own son at times but at other times treats him as more of a commodity
<br>In a deeply nested piece of irony, he is an extremely private person, harshly contrasting his own show
<br>
Meryl Burbank<br><br>
<br>Is a character in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> life played by Hannah Gill (actual character name)
<br>Married to <a data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman Burbank</a>
<br>Is offered a pay rise to have a child with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a> and is additionally paid $10,000 every time she sleeps with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a>
<br>Often blatantly weaves product placement into her conversations
<br>Works as an emergency room nurse
<br>
Marlon<br><br>
<br>Played by the character Louis Coltrane
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> best friend since childhood
<br>Works as a vending machine filler/repairman
<br>Another one of [Christof]'s manipulative proxies to control Truman
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman</a> often confides in him. <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> will speak through Marlon to manipulate him
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\character-profiles.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Character Profiles.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Language]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Costume
<br>Props
<br>Use of Colour -&gt; Setting, Costumes, Seahaven vs reality
<br>Use of Voiceover
<br>Dialogue -&gt; Omniscient 
<br>Tone -&gt; Satire
<br>Camera Angles -&gt; High, Low
<br>Camera Shots -&gt;Extreme close up, close up, establishing shot, over the shoulder shot, mid shot, full shot
<br>Symbolism/Allusions -&gt; Names, Props, Dialogue
<br>Score -&gt; Emotive
<br>Body Language
<br>Camera Movement -&gt; Panning
<br>CGI
<br>Lighting
<br><br>
<br>Auteur theory
<br>Mise-en-scene
<br>Sound and music
<br>Cinematography / Camera work
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\cinematic-techniques.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Cinematic Techniques.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Explain how "The Truman Show" invites us into another world &amp; broadens our understanding of the Human Experience]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Setting: Seahaven
<br>Director: Peter Weir
<br>Themes: Manipulation, Reality, Consumerism/Commercialism, Utopia/Dystopia
<br>Human Experience: Physical, Mental, Emotional, Spiritual
<br>Question Verb: "How?" -&gt; Techniques
<br><br>
<br>General comment on the nature of the question
<br>Introduce your thesis and how it intersects with the question (thesis is your position on the question)
<br>Introduce text(s)
<br>Brief reference to narratives of the text(s)
<br><br><br>
<br>Thesis: Many composers explore the concerns of manipulation and consumerism as a way to draw readers into alternate worlds and develop a deeper comprehension of the human experience.
<br><br>
<br>Manipulation

<br>Truman's fathers death manipulates Truman into staying on the island by manifesting a fear of water
<br>Truman's love life is controlled and he is manipulated into marrying Meryl. His true love is Sylvia


<br>Commercialism

<br>Truman and Marlon play golf off a bridge
<br>Meryl promotes the Chef's Pal


<br><br>Many composers explore the concerns of manipulation and consumerism as a way to draw readers into alternate worlds and develop a deeper comprehension of the human experience. Peter Weirs, "The Truman Show", is a prime example of this journey into the way humans experience reality. In The Truman Show, manipulation and commercialism are explored through Christof's extortion and control of Truman's everyday life. Truman's environment and hometown, Seahaven, is artificially constructed, manipulated, and broadcast to the world, 24/7 as part of a commercialised and voyeuristic reality TV production aptly named, The Truman Show.<br>Manipulation is inherently the most prominent idea traversed in The Truman Show. Christof, the director of the fictional show, created what is considered the world's greatest TV show based on a 24/7 live broadcast of Truman Burbank's everyday life. Truman's entire environment is constructed and controlled by Christof, inviting ideas of a god-like complex and manipulation into the protagonist's life. A prime example of the depth of manipulation Christof possesses in Seahaven is during Truman's father's death. Christof purposely fakes the drowning of the main character's father while they are on a sailing trip together, with the intention of scaring him to remain on the island of Seahaven. The effects of this manipulation are present throughout the film, including when Truman tries to catch a ferry to a neighbouring island but ultimately hurries away in fear after being provoked by the sight of a sunken dingy next to the pier. The use of "mise-en-scene" in placement of the dingy by Christof and Peter Weir's use of camera angles and shots showing Truman's gaze, visually demonstrates to the audience the extent of manipulation Christof has in Truman’s life.<br>
//TODO: Travel agent manipulation. "I'm sorry, I don't have anything for at least a month"<br>
Manipulation of Truman through the full extent of his environment, addresses the thematic interests of how manipulation affects how a human experiences life, making The Truman Show a real and relevant composition that viewers are drawn into.<br>In a world run by capitalist ideologies, The Truman show is no exception when it comes to advertisements and product placement in its 24/7 agenda. As Truman navigates his everyday life, the people around him whom he considers his closest, actively seek to display and promote new products to the audience watching, while masking it as a suggestion to Truman. This often reflects the real world where TV is fueled by rampant consumerism and the fear of missing out on the “new best thing”, closely relating this text to a viewer's reality. This only layers onto the mental manipulation Truman experiences everyday of his life. A perfect example of product placement comes from Truman’s wife, Meryl, when she returns from the supermarket to find him gardening. She turns to Truman with a “Chef’s Pal” in her hands and states “It's a dicer, grater, peeler, all in one. Never needs sharpening, dishwasher safe!”. Meryl’s choice of words provide the snappy and catchy language successful advertisements utilise, clearly bringing to light her commercial interest and the manipulation the fictional viewers of The Truman Show suffer. Near the end of the film Meryl makes another attempt at recommending a product to Truman in an attempt to change the conversation as Truman begins to realise his surroundings are all a facade for something bigger. Meryl tries to sell Truman some Mococoa chocolate drink powder saying , “Why don't you let me fix you some of this Mococoa drink? All natural cocoa beans from the upper slopes of Mount Nicaragua. No artificial sweeteners.“. This prompts Truman to look around and respond with “What the hell are you talking about?”. Truman understands that her choice of language is not usual or normal to any conversation between them and further pushes his idea that the world around him is not as he initially thought. Throughout all of Meryl’s product placement scenes, a zooming close up shot is formed onto her face and the product as she switches into advertisement mode, creating a sense of importance in the product being displayed.  This commercialistic venture propels viewers to become aware of Truman’s manipulative and simulated reality and begs them to reflect on their own situations, generating a relationship of similarity between their own and the protagonist's world, drawing them into the narrative.<br>Peter Weir’s The Truman Show meaningfully explores ideas of manipulation and consumerism in order to grab the attention of viewers and bring them into alternate worlds. These ideas are investigated through Christof's godlike extortion and control of Truman's everyday life in the town of Seahaven. Peter Weir, and consequently Christof, offer a wide range of cinematic and textual techniques including; word choice, camera shots and angles, and mise-en-scene, to construct a solid foundation for understanding how humans perceive and understand reality.]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\essay-draft-2024-03-04.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Essay Draft 2024-03-04.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introduction Scaffold]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>General comment on the nature of the question
<br>Introduce your thesis and how it intersects with the question (thesis is your position on the question)
<br>Introduce text(s)
<br>Brief reference to narratives of the text(s)
<br><br><br>
<br>Diametrically opposed
<br>Protagonist
<br>Antagonist
<br>Biblical allusion
<br><br>
<br>Utopia/Dystopia -&gt; Setting, costume -&gt; Artificial Reality
<br>Media's Manipulation -&gt; Commercialism
<br><br>
<br>"How" -&gt; Discuss Peter Weir's view, Use of techniques
<br>What is your thesis/underlying argument?

<br>Power In Relationships -&gt; Balance


<br><br>Many individuals in relationships experience abuse of power and extortion. Many texts explore this theme of abuse of power in relationships as a central and pivotal theme. In Peter Weirs' film, The Truman Show, abuse of power in relationships and related ideas are explored through Christof's extortion and control of Truman's everyday life. Truman's environment and hometown, Seahaven, is artificially constructed, manipulated, and broadcast to the world, 24/7 as part of a voyeuristic reality TV production aptly named, The Truman Show.<br><br>
<br>Limits of Simulated Reality
<br>Techniques:<br>
<br>Mis en Scene
<br>Camera angles
<br>Costumes
<br>Allusions
<br><br>Reality is a naturally complex system and difficult subject to replicate. The Truman Show makes an attempt at simulating an entire town centred around the protagonist, Truman Burbank, in order to control his environment. Christof fabricates an enormous film set called Seahaven, where Truman is manipulated into staying. Although the set is a technical marvel, it introduces the limits of simulated reality.<br>
In the very first scene of the film, the audience is oriented into Trumans life, the town of Seahaven, and his neighbours via a range of camera angles, dialogue choices and costume design. As he gets to his car, a stage light falls from the sky and crashes on the road. The light is also labelled "Sirius", which is a constellation and considered the brightest star in the sky, alluding to Truman, that his reality is secretly controlled. This outlines the limits of his reality, and it's fragility.]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\essay-practice-2024-02-20.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Essay Practice 2024-02-20.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Essay Practice 2024-02-27]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Vital
<br>Critical
<br><br>
<br>The Truman Show
<br><br>
<br>Internal/External
<br>Meryl/Truman
<br>Christof/Truman
<br><br>
<br>Themes: Power of The Media/Media and Manipulation
<br>Examples
<br>Techniques
<br><br>Dramatic conflict is a vital component to audience engagement in The Truman Show. Peter Weir conjugates dramatic conflict and power of the media to highlight Christof's manipulative behaviour towards Truman and his simulated reality to the viewer. When Truman makes an attempt to leave Seahaven by ferry, he's caught frozen in fear on the pier after his gaze meets a sunken dingy. Weir's use of camera angles to dictate Truman's gaze, and Christof's use of mis en scene in placement of the sunken boat, clearly indicate to the audience Christof's attempts to manipulate the protagonist to stay on the island.]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\essay-practice-2024-02-27.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Essay Practice 2024-02-27.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How does Peter Weir use characterisation to evoke significant ideas about the film "The Truman Show"]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>Many composers explore the thematic ideas surrounding characterisation through manipulation, consumerism and voyeurism as a way to present thoughts and considerations about texts.<br><br>
<br>Manipulation

<br>Truman's fathers death manipulates Truman into staying on the island by manifesting a fear of water
<br>Truman's love life is controlled and he is manipulated into marrying Meryl. His true love is Sylvia
<br>Travel agent tries to discourage Truman from going to Fiji. "I'm sorry, I don't have anything for at least a month"


<br>Commercialism

<br>Truman and Marlon play golf off a bridge
<br>Meryl promotes the Chef's Pal


]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\essay-practice-2024-03-11.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Essay Practice 2024-03-11.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[To what extent is Wier's use of language responsible for widening your perspective of conformity and deception.]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Deception: The act of causing someone to accept as true or valid
<br>Conformity: Correspondence in form, manner, or character : agreement
<br><br>Cinematic techniques are utilised in films to explore the thematic concerns of their textual basis. Peter Weir]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\essay-practice-2024-03-18.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Essay Practice 2024-03-18.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scene Analysis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\scene-analysis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Scene Analysis.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seahaven]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br><br><br>Seahaven<br><br>]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\seahaven.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Seahaven.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Symbolism in The Truman Show]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Aside from the obvious (Christof, creator and creation motif), there are small things such as a reference to psalm 139.
<br><br>
<br>Truman Burbank - Burbank Studio California (a closed film set)
<br>Santa Maria - Columbus' ship finding the new world
<br>Sirius The Dog Star - "Dog Days" or madness in the people
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\symbolism-in-the-truman-show.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Symbolism in The Truman Show.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Themes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>"The Truman Show" blurs the lines between reality and fiction<br><br>"The Truman Show" is a satire and contains a thinly veiled religious allegory. The aptly names <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> is a mysterious character with a God complex who uses his omnipresence to control Truman. Similarly, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> audiences are complicity in his entrapment, as <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> would be powerless without their attention<br><br><a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a> created Seahaven in his vision of utopia. This doesn't align with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> idea of a utopia making <a data-href="Christof" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\christof.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Christof</a>'s utopia, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Truman Burbank" data-href="Truman Burbank" href="\module-b-the-truman-show\characters\truman-burbank.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Truman's</a> dystopia<br>]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\themes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Themes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Word List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Tyranny - Dictatorship, Totalitarianism
<br>Appraise - Assess, Evaluate
<br>Ideas - Concepts, Thematic Concerns
<br>Detailed Textual Knowledge - Examples, Techniques, Quotes, Context, Ideas, Dialogue, Scenes,
<br><br>
<br>Diametrically - (with reference to opposition) completely; directly
]]></description><link>module-b-the-truman-show\word-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module B -The Truman Show/Word List.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linda Burney's Speech]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>MP Linda Burney gave the moving first indigenous female speech at parliament
<br><br>
<br>Metaphor
<br>Jargon
<br>Hyperbole
<br>Personal Anecdote
<br>Cliché -&gt; "This land was, is, and always will be Aboriginal land"
<br>Props
]]></description><link>module-c-craft-of-writing\linda-burney's-speech.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module C - Craft of Writing/Linda Burney's Speech.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Syllabus Summary]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>In Module C, students will strengthen their knowledge, skills and confidence in writing. They will write for a wide range of audiences and convey a range of ideas with power and increasing precision.]]></description><link>module-c-craft-of-writing\syllabus-summary.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module C - Craft of Writing/Syllabus Summary.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Pedestrian]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>To enter out into that silence that was the city at eight o'clock of a misty evening in November, to put your feet upon that buckling concrete walk, to step over grassy seams and make your way, hands in pockets, through the silences, that was what Mr. Leonard Mead most dearly loved to do. He would stand upon the corner of an intersection and peer down long moonlit avenues of sidewalk in four directions, deciding which way to go, but it really made no difference; he was alone in this world of A.D. 2053, or as good as alone, and with a final decision made, a path selected, he would stride off, sending patterns of frosty air before him like the smoke of a cigar. Sometimes he would walk for hours and miles and return only at midnight to his house. And on his way he would see the cottages and homes with their dark windows, and it was not unequal to walking through a graveyard where only the faintest glimmers of firefly light appeared in flickers behind the windows. Sudden gray phantoms seemed to manifest upon inner room walls where a curtain was still undrawn against the night, or there were whisperings and murmurs where a window in a tomblike building was still open. Mr. Leonard Mead would pause, cock his head, listen, look, and march on, his feet making no noise on the lumpy walk. For long ago he had wisely changed to sneakers when strolling at night, because the dogs in intermittent squads would parallel his journey with barkings if he wore hard heels, and lights might click on and faces appear and an entire street be startled by the passing of a lone figure, himself, in the early November evening. On this particular evening he began his journey in a westerly direction, toward the hidden sea. There was a good crystal frost in the air; it cut the nose and made the lungs blaze like a Christmas tree inside; you could feel the cold light going on and off, all the branches filled with invisible snow. He listened to the faint push of his soft shoes through autumn leaves with satisfaction, and whistled a cold quiet whistle between his teeth, occasionally picking up a leaf as he passed, examining its skeletal pattern in the infrequent lamplights as he went on, smelling its rusty smell. "Hello, in there," he whispered to every house on every side as he moved. "What's up tonight on Channel 4, Channel 7, Channel 9? Where are the cowboys rushing, and do I see the United States Cavalry over the next hill to the rescue?" The street was silent and long and empty, with only his shadow moving like the shadow of a hawk in midcountry. If he closed his eyes and stood very still, frozen, he could imagine himself upon the center of a plain, a wintry, windless Arizona desert with no house in a thousand miles, and only dry river beds, the streets, for company. "What is it now?" he asked the houses, noticing his wrist watch. "Eight-thirty P.M.? Time for a dozen assorted murders? A quiz? A revue? A comedian falling off the stage?" Was that a murmur of laughter from within a moon-white house? He hesitated, but went on when nothing more happened. He stumbled over a particularly uneven section of sidewalk. The cement was vanishing under flowers and grass. In ten years of walking by night or day, for thousands of miles, he had never met another person walking, not once in all that time. He came to a cloverleaf intersection which stood silent where two main highways crossed the town. During the day it was a thunderous surge of cars, the gas stations open, a great insect rustling and a ceaseless jockeying for position as the scarabbeetles, a faint incense puttering from their exhausts, skimmed homeward to the far directions. But now these highways, too, were like streams in a dry season, all stone and bed and moon radiance. He turned back on a side street, circling around toward his home. He was within a block of his destination when the lone car turned a corner quite suddenly and flashed a fierce white cone of light upon him. He stood entranced, not unlike a night moth, stunned by the illumination, and then drawn toward it. A metallic voice called to him: "Stand still. Stay where you are! Don't move!" He halted. "Put up your hands!" "But-" he said. "Your hands up! Or we'll Shoot!" The police, of course, but what a rare, incredible thing; in a city of three million, there was only one police car left, wasn't that correct? Ever since a year ago, 2052, the election year, the force had been cut down from three cars to one. Crime was ebbing; there was no need now for the police, save for this one lone car wandering and wandering the empty streets. "Your name?" said the police car in a metallic whisper. He couldn't see the men in it for the bright light in his eyes. "Leonard Mead," he said. "Speak up!" "Leonard Mead!" "Business or profession?" "I guess you'd call me a writer." "No profession," said the police car, as if talking to itself. The light held him fixed, like a museum specimen, needle thrust through chest. "You might say that, " said Mr. Mead. He hadn't written in years. Magazines and books didn't sell any more. Everything went on in the tomblike houses at night now, he thought, continuing his fancy. The tombs, ill-lit by television light, where the people sat like the dead, the gray or multicolored lights touching their faces, but never really touching them. "No profession," said the phonograph voice, hissing. "What are you doing out?" "Walking," said Leonard Mead. "Walking!" "Just walking," he said simply, but his face felt cold. "Walking, just walking, walking?" "Yes, sir." "Walking where? For what?" "Walking for air. Walking to see." "Your address!" "Eleven South Saint James Street." "And there is air in your house, you have an air conditioner, Mr. Mead?" "Yes." "And you have a viewing screen in your house to see with?" "No." "No?" There was a crackling quiet that in itself was an accusation. "Are you married, Mr. Mead?" "No." "Not married," said the police voice behind the fiery beam, The moon was high and clear among the stars and the houses were gray and silent. "Nobody wanted me," said Leonard Mead with a smile. "Don't speak unless you're spoken to!" Leonard Mead waited in the cold night. "Just walking, Mr. Mead?" "Yes." "But you haven't explained for what purpose." "I explained; for air, and to see, and just to walk." "Have you done this often?" "Every night for years." The police car sat in the center of the street with its radio throat faintly humming. "Well, Mr. Mead," it said. "Is that all?" he asked politely. "Yes," said the voice. "Here." There was a sigh, a pop. The back door of the police car sprang wide. "Get in." "Wait a minute, I haven't done anything!" "Get in." "I protest!" "Mr. Mead." He walked like a man suddenly drunk. As he passed the front window of the car he looked in. As he had expected, there was no one in the front seat, no one in the car at all. "Get in." He put his hand to the door and peered into the back seat, which was a little cell, a little black jail with bars. It smelled of riveted steel. It smelled of harsh antiseptic; it smelled too clean and hard and metallic. There was nothing soft there. "Now if you had a wife to give you an alibi," said the iron voice. "But-" "Where are you taking me?" The car hesitated, or rather gave a faint whirring click, as if information, somewhere, was dropping card by punch-slotted card under electric eyes. "To the Psychiatric Center for Research on Regressive Tendencies." He got in. The door shut with a soft thud. The police car rolled through the night avenues, flashing its dim lights ahead. They passed one house on one street a moment later, one house in an entire city of houses that were dark, but this one particular house had all of its electric lights brightly lit, every window a loud yellow illumination, square and warm in the cool darkness. "That's my house," said Leonard Mead. No one answered him. The car moved down the empty river-bed streets and off away, leaving the empty streets with the empty side-walks, and no sound and no motion all the rest of the chill November night.<br><br>Who - Leonard Mead<br>
What -<br>
When - 2053 AD<br>
Where - ]]></description><link>module-c-craft-of-writing\the-pedestrian.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module C - Craft of Writing/The Pedestrian.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How Meaning Is Made]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Meaning is made when the responder comes to an understanding of texts
<br>There are two important areas to consider

<br>What the text means
<br>How meaning is made


<br>It is a good idea to think of a "how meaning is made" question as having 3 parts

<br>What is happening
<br>What techniques are used by the author to influence the reader's thinking/understanding/response
<br>What do the first two questions do to my understanding of human experience


<br>Prose: paragraph structure, sentence construction, punctuation, language level, imagery, word choice, etc.
<br>Poetry: stanza construction and length, imagery, sound techniques, etc.
<br>Visual: framing, use of colour, positioning of people and objects, figurative language, etc.
<br>Lyrics: textual and musical features
]]></description><link>how-meaning-is-made.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">How Meaning Is Made.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Welcome to Daniel's HSC English notes! Please checkout the page explorer on the left to navigate this site]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:43:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Word List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The Crucible Word List<br><br>
<br>Fervour: noun Intense and passionate feeling
<br>Ostracise: verb Exclude from a group or society
<br>McCarthyism: 

<br>verb The political practice of publicizing accusations of disloyalty or subversion with insufficient regard to evidence 
<br>noun The use of methods of investigation and accusation regarded as unfair, in order to suppress opposition


]]></description><link>word-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Word List.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:38:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HSC Revision]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>Groups -&gt; Bushmen, Australian Women, Union Members<br>
Adaption to change -&gt; Resilience, Masculine, Harsh Conditions<br>Adaption to change is an important theme addressed by many of Henry Lawsons texts. The Drovers Wife, The Loaded Dog, and The Union Buries Its Dead all express the resilience and masculinity characters form through their emotionally shaping adaptations to harsh environments.<br><br><br>Affirmed Stereotypes -&gt; Depiction of Australian women are strong and resilient<br>Related Text: The Loaded Dog<br>
Affirmed Stereotypes -&gt; Larrikin-like and humorous nature of Australian Bushmen<br>Thesis: The affirmation of cultural voice with employed stereotypes forms a repetitive motif in Henry Lawson's texts.<br>Intro: The affirmation of cultural voice with employed stereotypes forms a repetitive motif in Henry Lawson's texts. <br><br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>module-a-henry-lawson\hsc-revision.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module A - Henry Lawson/HSC Revision.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 02:35:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Imaginative Piece]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>module-c-craft-of-writing\speak-your-mind-tasks\imaginative-piece.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module C - Craft of Writing/Speak Your Mind Tasks/Imaginative Piece.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:41:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sky High]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>module-c-craft-of-writing\sky-high.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module C - Craft of Writing/Sky High.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 14:25:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Word List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>module-c-craft-of-writing\word-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Module C - Craft of Writing/Word List.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:41:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>